Guide to the Hanover Royal Music Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Music Collections, 1651-1868; Series II; 3.25; (132 boxes)
  - Manuscript Music Books
    - Unidentified
      - Music book, circa 1780s (Box 825)
        Bound with: Journal hebdomadaire...22 Année. No.52 (Toi que j'aimai). Print (Paris: le Duc, [1780s]), paginated 122-123, with contemporary manuscript annotations
      - Music book, circa 1794 (Box 826)
        Contains songs; sketches and drafts, possibly by Princess Augusta or other Princesses; Charles Frederick Horn (Sonata, violin/oboe/flute and piano, op. 3, no. 1, first movement, sketches; and other sketches)
      - Music book, circa 1818 (Box 183, Folder 945)
        Disbound
        Contains mostly transcriptions of dances and songs, including by Felice Blangini, Alday, and Daniel Steibelt; drafts and sketches in various hands, one dated 1818
      - Music book, circa 1819 (Box 183, Folder 946)
        Contains mostly song transcriptions, including sketches, one dated 1819; some possibly in the hand of Princess Augusta
      - Music book. Psalms and Hymns Sung at the Parish Church of New Windsor, circa 1825 (Box 827)
        Book binder's label: W. Perryman...Windsor
        In one unidentified hand
      - Music book, early 19th century (Box 828)
        Contains songs in several hands
      - Music book, early 19th century (Box 829)
        Contains songs, piano music, and sketches
      - Music book, circa 1829-1839 (Box 830)
        Cover title: Englische Gesänge
        Contains song transcriptions, in various unidentified hands; Johann Christian Bach, (holograph setting of Pope's ode "The dying [expiring] Christian to his soul); music possibly in the hand of a member of the royal family; O salutaris hostia, titled Motet à trios voix sans accompagnement par gossec
      - Music book, undated (Box 831)
        Contains songs
      - Music book, undated (Box 832)
        Inscribed: Augusta, [Olga?], Mary, Sophie, Amelia
      - Music book, undated (Box 833)
        Contains songs, glees, canzonets, and other music, including by Giovanni Paisiello, Jackson, William Shield, Thomas Augustine Arne, Johann Paul Aegidius Martini, Gioacchino Cocchi and others
      - Music book, undated (Box 834)
        Inscribed: J. M. Bremeyer
        Contains chorales, in German
      - Music book, undated (Box 835)
        Book seller's ticket: Mayr and Fessler, Vienna
        Contains exercises
        Laid in: postcard with notes in German
      - Major and minor keys in three positions. Manuscript, undated (Box 183, Folder 947)
      - Other manuscript music collections, undated (Box 184, Folder 948)
      - Other manuscript music collections, undated (Box 836)
  - Bound Collections
    - Bound collection, 1788, undated (Box 837)
      Inscribed, in the hand of Frederick Nicolay: This volume belongs to the Queen, 1788
      Contains: Johann Christian Bach, [Sonatas, harpsichord, violin, violoncello, W. B 43-48]. Six Sonates pour le clavecin...Oeuvre II, (London: Welcker); and music by Abel, Ricci, Pugnani, Alessandri, Michaelis and Pellegrino
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 838)
      Cover title: Compositionen für das Piano Forte
      Contains piano parts for: Ludwig van Beethoven, [Trios, piano, strings, op. 1], Trois Trios pour le Pianoforte, Violon et Violoncell...Nouvelle Edition (Leipzig: Peters; Prince Louis Ferdinand, Quatuor Pour le Piano-Forte Violon, Viole et Violoncelle... (Leipzig: Breitkopf)
      With parts for violin and violoncello, and viola part for Prince Louis Ferdinand, Quatuor
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 839)
      Contains violoncello parts for: Muzio Clementi, [Sonatas, piano, flute, violoncello, op. 21], Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord, with Accompaniments for a Flute and Violoncello (London: Longman & Broderip); Ignaz Pleyel, Six Sonatas For the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an accompaniment for a flute or violin & violoncello... (London: Longman & Broderip); and Charles Frederick Horn, [Sonatas, keyboard, violin, violoncello, op. 1], Six sonatas....
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 840)
      Cover title: P. A. Sonatas & Violoncello
      Contains piano and violoncello parts for: Muzio Clementi, [Sonatas, piano, flute, violoncello, op. 22], Three Sonatas for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord With Accompaniments for a flute and violoncello.... (London: J. Dale)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 184-185, Folder 949-952)
      Set of string quartet parts, containing: Adalbert Gyrowetz, Six Quatuors... Oeuvre 1er. (Paris: Imbault), Tre Quartetti…Opera 29 (Vienna: Artaria); Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, including Mozart's Celebrated opera Zauberflöte, Arranged as Quartetts... (London: Kauntze), [Sonata, violin and piano, K. 378], arranged for string quartet by W. Watts (Manchester: T. Beale; London: Preston); Ignaz Pleyel, An Eighth Sett of Six Quartettos...Op.23 (London: for W. Forster); Giuliani, Quatuor periodique... No. 1 and No. 5 (Offenbach: André)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 841)
      Spine title: Violin music
      Contains: Federigo Fiorillo, Studio per il Violino.... (Naples: Marescalchi); Giuseppe Tartini, [Sonatas, violin, continuo, B. g 5, G minor], The Celebrated Sonata del Diavolo.... (London: Sibley); Claus Nielsen Schall, Six Solos...Op.1.... (London: Bland); J. B. (Jean Baptiste) Bréval, Six Duets...Op XIX.... (London: Preston)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 842)
      Cover title: H. R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Harp music
      First item signed by Princess Augusta
      Contains music for harp, including by Marsano, Egan, Fiorillo, and Boieldieu
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 843)
      Spine title: Miscellany
      Contains: Johann Christian Bach, Four Sonatas and Two Duetts for the Harpsichord or Piano Forte...Opera 18 (London: for the Proprietor); Venanzio Rauzzini, Six Sonatas for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord...Op.8 (London: for the Proprietor, [1781]); Johann Samuel Schroeter, Six Concertos for the Harpsichord...Opera V (London: Napier), Six Concertos for the Harpsichord or Piano Forte...Opera III (London: Napier), harpsichord parts only; music by Giordani, Noferi. and Ferdinand Staes
    - Bound collection, 1802-1830, undated (Box 844)
      Contains keyboard music, including: Ludwig van Beethoven, Grande Sonate...Oeuvre 26 (Frankfurt: Dunst [after 1830]), Sonata quasi una Fantasia...Opera 27, No.1 (Bonn: N. Simrock, [1802]), Sonata quasi una Fantasia...Oeuv: 27, No. 2 (Bonn: N. Simrock, [1802]); and works by Greulich, Jane Robinson, and others
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 845)
      Cover title: Gesangs Kompositionen von Curschmann
      Contains keyboard music and songs, including by Fr. (Friedrich) Curschman and Georg V
    - Bound collection, 1835, undated (Box 846)
      Cover title: Tänze und Gesangscompositionen
      Contains piano music and songs, including: Georg V, as Prince George of Cumberland, Great Waltz...., dedicated to William IV (Berlin: Westphal); Greulich, Quatre grandes Marches; M.A. Zani de Ferranti, God save the King, 1835); and Carl Maria von Weber, Einzelne Gesangstücke aus Oberon, with stamp of Princess Augusta
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 847)
      Title cover: H. R. H. Princess Augusta, Lessons
      Contains keyboard music: Charles Frederick Horn, Six Sonatas for the Piano Forte…opera prima (London: author); Muzio Clementi, Three Sonatas...Op.XXI (London: Longman & Broderip); Ignaz Pleyel, Six Sonatas (London: Longman & Broderip), Two Grand Sonatas...Op.7 (London: Bland), Sonata for the Piano Forte (London: Longman & Broderip)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 848)
      Cover title: H.R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Piano Forte Music
      One item signed by Princess Augusta; many inscribed "Good"
      Contains music for keyboard, including: Nicolas-Joseph Hüllmandel, Trois Sonates, Op.XI (Paris: Saunier); Joseph Haydn, The Celebrated Overture (London: Longman); Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, opera excerpts arranged by Federigo Fiorillo
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 849)
      Cover title: A. S.
      Contains music for piano, including: Kurpinski; Haub; Walch; C. Preuss; C. F. Ebers, Six Polonoises, inscribed by Princes Augusta; Hummel
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 850)
      Cover title: H. R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Piano Forte Music
      Book binder's label: W. Perryman…Windsor
      Contains keyboard music including works and arrangements of works by Mencke; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, K. 501 (André); Georges Onslow; Charles Frederick Horn; Hart; Gaspare Spontini
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 851)
      Cover title: H. R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Overture
      Book binder's label: W. Perryman, Windsor
      Contains piano music, mostly arrangements of overtures by Gioacchino Rossini, including Semiramide, Tancredi, Il Turco in Italia, Conradino, Cenerentola, Mose in Egitto, La Donna del Lago, La gazza ladra, Otello, L'ingano felice
    - Bound collection, 1824, undated (Box 852)
      Contains piano music, including: Spaeth, op.73; Hummel; Bauer, VI Münchner Ländler...1824; Bernlochner; Sörgel; Loebeis, Spiker; Zulehner; Wilde; Seiff; Weber; Kloss
    - Bound collection, 1788?-1797, undated (Box 853)
      Inscribed: Amelia, 1798 Janry 12, Windsor
      Some items signed by Princess Amelia
      Contains keyboard music, including: Steibelt; Dussek; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, A Duet for two Performers... Op. 3, K.381 (London: Birchall, [circa 1797]), signed by Princess Augusta; Muzio Clementi, Clementi's Grand Sonata...Op.XXX (London: Dale), Three Sonatas...Op.XXI, (London: Longman & Broderip, [1788?]), piano parts only; Joseph Haydn, [Symphony, H. I, 97, C major], Haydn's Celebrated Overture [Composed for & performed at Mr. Salomon's Concert Hanover-Square...No.1 (London: Corri, Dussek & Co., [circa.1796]), signed by John Peter Salomon; George Frideric Handel, Overture in Esther, paginated 19-24, manuscript annotations; Kozeluch. Three Sonatas...Op.40 (London: F. Linley, [1796]) piano part only; and others; manuscript music in an unidentified hand
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 854)
      Inscribed: Her Royal Highness The Duchess of Cumberland
      Contains print and manuscript piano music, including: Weller; A. (August) Neithardt; and Johann Strauss
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 855)
      Cover title: Walzer
      Contains keyboard music: waltzes by Johann Strauss, 1804-1849, including Op.40, 49, 60, 63 and 65; music by F. Weller
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 856)
      Cover title: H.R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Waltzes
      Contains waltzes arranged for piano
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 857-860)
      Four volumes containing vocal music, including: by "an amateur," Odes, Songs, and Marches (London: author); Gesualdo Lanza, jun., God Save the King (London: J. Muff); Rosselli, Rasserena il mesto ciglio, A Favorite Rondo (London: author); Hawes, The Kiss (London: Goulding); Dibdin; Charles Edward Horn, including two items signed by him; Charles Frederick Horn, Trafalgar, an Heroic Song (London: Goulding), initialled by him; Waller; Bruguier; C. H. Campbell; T. Cooke; G. W. Hollis; and others
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 861)
      Inscribed: Cheveley
      Contains keyboard and vocal music, including: Tenducci, one item signed by him; Giordani; and others
      Bound with Johann Christian Bach, [Gioas, rè di Giuda], T'adoro te solo eterno mio Dio, holograph, circa 1770
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 862)
      Cover title: H. R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Vocal Music
      Contains vocal music, including: Felice Blangini; Kreutzer; Nasolini; Gioacchino Rossini; Charles Edward Horn; Bishop; William Hawes
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 863)
      Cover title: H.R.H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Vocal Music
      Contains vocal music, including: Crescentini; Cimarosa; Sola; Bianchi, signed by Lorenzo da Ponte; Mazzinghi; Horn; Arne; Bishop; Stephen Storace
    - Bound collection, 1809-1830, undated (Box 864)
      Contains vocal vocal music, including: Dibdin, God Save King William (London: T. Welsh, [1830]); F. Ireland, To Love & Wine (London: Bland); Harrington, A Favorite Collection of Songs, Glees, Elegies & Canons (Longman & Broderip); Serres, Poor Barbara! A Plaintive Ballad (London: Caldicot, 1809), inscribed to the Princess Augusta); and Deponti
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 865)
      Cover title: Italienische Gesänge
      Contains print and manuscript vocal music, including: Garcia,Caprichos liricos españoles (London: author); Zaniboni, Six Italian Canzonetts, and Eight Divertimentos (London: author), signed by the composer; Mozart, [Don Giovanni], Deh vieni, vocal score, manuscript; Notturno a due Voci, manuscript, in an unidentified hand; song, manuscript, apparently in the hand of Princess Augusta
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 866)
      Cover title: Deutsche u. Französis. Gesänge
      Contains print and manuscript arias and songs, including: Gluck, [Die Pilgrime von Mecca], Schönste dein Reiz and Einen Bach der fliesst, manuscript copies, 18th century; C. Keller; E. Zumsteeg; Hetsch; Haizinger; Himmel; Charles Frederick Horn, Geduld, hymn, apparently holograph; others
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 867)
      On cover: monograph of Princess Augusta
      Contains vocal music, including: F. H. Himmel, Gebet während der Schlacht; Carl Nicola; Wilhelm Speier; Lindpaintner; Blangini; Weber, Gesänge und Lieder (Berlin: Schlesinger), Sechs Gesänge...Op.23 (Berlin: in der Schlesingerschen Musikhandlung); Morlacchi; Rossini, Der Barbier von Sevilla, arranged by Riotte (Vienna: Steiner)
      With song, manuscript, possibly in then hand of Princess Augusta
    - Bound collection, 1809, undated (Box 868)
      Contains vocal music, including: Charles Frederick Horn, Hark the loud Trumpet (London: author), initialled by the composer); Charles Edward Horn, Make ready, Present, Fire (London: Goulding), initialled by the composer; Bedoyere, Six Romances (London: author), signed by the composer; Bremner, A Second Set of Scots Songs, adapted for the Voice and Harpsichord (London: Preston); God Save the King, anonymous setting for the fiftieth anniversary of the reign of George III (no place: no publisher, October 25th 1809)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 869)
      Cover title: Französ. u. Deutsche Gesänge
      Contains print and manuscript vocal music, including: Madame R. H. M., Ariette du Deserteur, arranged (no publisher): Bedoyere, Six Romances...2e Recueil (London: author), signed by the composer, lacking pages 5-8; Meisenheimer Lied für das Piano Forte, manuscript, in an unidentified hand
    - Bound collection, 1815, undated (Box 870)
      Cover title: Gesang und Tanzcompositionen
      Contains piano music and songs, including: Marschner; Greulich; Klage; Mockwitz, Grand Septuor de Louis v. Beethoven arrange Pour le Piano-Forte à quatre mains (Leipzig: Breitkopf, 1815)
    - Bound collection, 1795, undated (Box 871)
      Contains print and manuscript songs and arias, including Paisiello, [La Molinara], Duetto, Nel Cor piu non mi sento, per il Clavicembalo (Vienna: Artaria, [circa 1795]); Agrippino Rosselli, Duettini...Con accompagamento di Fortepiano, manuscript; Salieri, [Axur, re d'Ormus], rondo, Son queste le Speranze, and cavatina, Com' a pe ingegno, vocal score, manuscript
    - Bound collection, circa 1730, undated (Box 872)
      Spine title: Pepusch, Purcell, Blow, &c
      Contains:John Christopher Pepusch, Six English Cantatas (London: J. Walsh, [circa 1730]; Thesaurus Musicus, A Collection of two, three, and four Part Songs, 2 volumes (London: John Simpson)
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 873)
      Contains songs including: Niccolò Piccini, The Favorite Songs in the Opera Le Contadine Bizzarre, 2 volumes, (London: Bremner, The Favorite Songs in the Opera Gli Stravaganti, A Burletta (London: Bremner), La Schiava (London: Bremner); Alessandri, The Favourite Songs In the Opera La moglie fedele (London: Bremner); Pugnani, The Favourite Songs in the Comic Opera Nanetta e Lubino (London: Welcker)
      Laid in: manuscript music in an unidentified hand
    - Bound collection, 1779-1798, undated (Box 874)
      Contains print and manuscript songs, including: Shield, The Overture, Songs, Duetts &c in the Musical Farce of The Lock and Key (London: Preston); A. Rosselli, Four Canzonets (London: author), signed by Princess Augusta, 1798; Johann Christian Bach, [Rinaldo ed Armida. Io ti lascio questo addio] The first Favorite Rondeau Sung by Mr. Tenducci at Mess.rs Bach and Abel's Concert (London: Cahusac, [1790?]); Tenducci's Second Rondeau, 1779 (London: Cahusac); Elizabeth Turner, [Not, Chloris, that I juster am], words by Sir Charles Sedley (Lady's Magazine, Supplement, 1796); Holy, Holy, Holy, hymn, manuscript, possibly in a royal hand
    - Bound collection, 1788, undated (Box 185, Folder 953)
      Contains music for voices and for voices and harp, including: Stevens, Sigh no more Ladies, signed by M. Cheveley; Webbe, Prize Glee, 1788; E. Guilbert, Six Chansonnettes Francaises, op.1, signed by the composer
    - Bound collection, undated (Box 875)
      Cover title: H. R. H. Princess Augusta; spine title: Vocal music
      Contains music for voice and keyboard, including: original works and arrangements of works by Weber; Auber; Danzi; Mozart; Boieldieu; Beethoven; Häser
      Bound with: Sechs deutsche Lieder mit Begleitung des Pianoforte's, von Emilie Zumsteeg, manuscript
- Duke of Cumberland's Band Archive, circa 1765-1834; Series III; 9; (107 boxes)
  Series III, Duke of Cumberland's Band Archive, is organized by name of composer or arranger, and alphabetically by title within each name.
  Music consists of sets of parts, printed and copyist's manuscripts, used in performance by a private band employed in Great Britain by Ernest Augustus, Duke of Cumberland, later King of Hanover. This material is an apparently intact archive, with original annotated folders for each work, and a bound catalog listing contents. Though most music is undated, watermarks and preliminary conjectured dates span circa 1790-1810. A small amount of dated music extends this span from 1765 to1834. The catalog volume contains 1814 watermarks, as well as unrelated accounts in an unidentified hand, kept in England, 1838-1840.
  Most music is for band, typically clarinets, flute, bassoons, serpent, horns, trumpets, trombone, and timpani. Some works include additional woodwind, brass, or percussion, and some are for orchestra with strings, or for chamber ensembles. Much of the music is manuscript arrangements for band of orchestra works, including arrangements of works by Haydn, Mozart, and Beethoven. Also present is print and manuscript music composed for band, chamber ensembles, or orchestra, including a set of orchestral parts for Beethoven's Symphony No. 1, copyist's manuscript, watermarked 1804. Following music organized by composer name are works by unidentified composers, arranged alphabetically by title.
  Music is listed under either original composer or arranger, in accordance with annotations on original folders. Numbering on original folders is cited in folder notes, and may correspond to listings in the catalog volume. Many printed parts are annotated in manuscript, and some bear signatures, stamps, performance markings, or manuscript cancels or additions. A few works are accompanied by transcriptions in an unidentified 20th century hand. While some details of description are noted in folder notes, more evidence of use will likely be found through further examination.
  - Arne, Thomas Augustine, 1710-1778
    - [Artaxerxes. Overture]. Arranged by Henry Pick. Parts (2 ob, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, trbn, timp). Manuscript, undated (Box 186, Folder 954-957)
      Original folder: numbered 6 and 75
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    - [Adelaide]. Arranged. Parts (2 fl,1 ob, 4 cl, 3 bn, spt, trbn). Manuscript, undated (Box 187, Folder 958)
      Original folder: not present
    - Andante Cantabile. Arranged by Frederick Eley. Parts (1 fl, 4 cl, 2 bn (1 part), spt, 2 hn, tpt). Manuscript, undated (Box 187, Folder 959-960)
      Original folder: numbered 44 and 118
      Bassoon part inscribed: Michel Nardeman
    - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 21, C major]. Arranged by C. Kramer. Parts (3 fl, 5 cl, 2nd ob, 2 bn, spt, 1st hn, 2 tpt, 3 trbn, timp, unidentified). Manuscript, 1807? (Box 187, Folder 961-963)
      Original folder: numbered 45 and 102
      Watermark: 1807
    - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 21, C major]. Parts (2 vn, va, vc and b (2 copies), fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, trbn, timp). Manuscript, 1804? (Box 188, Folder 964-966)
      Original folder: numbered 9 and 63
      Watermark: 1804
    - [Trio]. Grand Trio pour Deux Hautbois et Basson. Parts (2 ob, bn or vc). Print (Bonn: N. Simrock), undated (Box 188, Folder 967-968)
      Original folder: numbered 19 and 13
      Manuscript cancels
    - [Trio]. Grand Trio. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, 2 trbn, timp). Manuscript, undated (Box 188-189, Folder 969-970)
      Original folder: numbered 31 and 119
  - Bianchi, F. (Francesco), ca. 1752-1810
    - [La morte de Cleopatra. Excerpt]. Theme sung by Madame Banti in the opera Le morte di Cleopatra. Arranged by J. Blayney. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 3 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt). Manuscript, undated (Box 189, Folder 971-972)
      Original folder: numbered 59 and 228
  - Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), Sir, 1786-1855
    - [Caractacus. Excerpt]. Andantino. Arranged by J. Blayney. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 2 cl, 3 bn (2 parts), spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part)). Manuscript, undated (Box 189, Folder 973-974)
      Original folder: numbered 53 and 295
  - Blayney, J., arranger
    - Eight Pieces arranged for a Military Band...selected from the most favorite Italian Operas..... Parts (2 fl, 2 cl, 2 bn and spt (2 parts), 2 hn, 2 tpt (1 part)). Print (London: Kelly), undated (Box 190, Folder 975-976)
      Original folder: numbered 51
    - Eight Pieces, Selected from the Favorite Operas of Calipso…. Parts (2 fl, 3 cl, 2 bn (1 part), spt, 2 hn, tpt). Print (London: Kelly), undated (Box 190, Folder 977-978)
      Original folder: numbered 14, 202, and 203
    - Italian Air. Parts (2 fl, 1 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn (1 part), spt 2 hn, tpt). Manuscript, undated (Box 190-191, Folder 979-980)
      Original folder: numbered 11 and 257
      With: Paër, Ferdinando. [I fuorusciti di Firenze. Overture]. Arranged. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 5 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, 2 tpt, trbn). Manuscript. Original folder: numbered 81
    - Sung by Madame Banti in the opera of Alzira, and military pieces. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 5 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt). Manuscript, undated (Box 191, Folder 981-983)
      Original folder: numbered 58 and 230
  - Boyce, William
    - Softly Rise O Southern Breeze. Arranged by Frederick Eley. Parts (1 fl, 6 cl, 3 bn and spt (3 parts), 2 hn (1 part)). Manuscript, undated (Box 191, Folder 984-985)
      Original folder: numbered 13 and 252
  - Braham, John, 1774-1856
    - [The Cabinet]. Arranged by Henry Pick. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 3 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, bugle, trbn, timp, triangle). Manuscript, undated (Box 192-193, Folder 986-990)
      Original folder: numbered 7
    - The Music In the English Fleet in 1342. Arranged by Henry Pick. Parts (2 fl, 1 ob, 2 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, bugle, trbn). Manuscript, undated (Box 193-194, Folder 991-995)
      Original folder: numbered 8 and 303
  - Brindley, George
    - Four Military Pieces. Parts (2 fl, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 195, Folder 996-997)
      Original folder: numbered 32
  - Carbonel, N. (Narcisse), 1773-1855